<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Iiams Family Genealogy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:52078/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Iiams Family Genealogy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 06:51:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:52078/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Summary of the Will of William Burgess (1622-1686)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52078/posts/004/william_burgess_will_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 06:51:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:52078/posts/004/william_burgess_will_analysis/</guid>
      <description>The will of William Burgess is preserved at the National Archives in London, one of only two wills from Anne Arundel colonists found in the English archives. With the assistance of ChatGPT, we transcribe and analyze this will to uncover insights into the life of William Burgess and, by extension, William Iiams.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New website features</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52078/posts/003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 20:51:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:52078/posts/003/</guid>
      <description>Introducing DataTables and improved image display capability</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who was William L. Iams (1872-1896)?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52078/posts/002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 06:51:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:52078/posts/002/</guid>
      <description>At the young age of 20 years old, while deployed as a member of the Pennsylvania Reserves, William Iams made an ill-advised cheer. What immediately followed was his torture by his own commanders nearly to the point of unconsciousness, literal tar and feathering out of camp, dismissal from the Army, and an national news spectacle with court-room drama.  And ultimately, his violent death only four years later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who was Raleigh Brown Ijams (1858-1907)?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52078/posts/001/rin_1635/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 06:51:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:52078/posts/001/rin_1635/</guid>
      <description>Raleigh Brown Ijams was born into a wealthy family in modern day West Virginia, raised in Baltimore and later lived in Manhattan. He engaged in a variety of business ventures. He never married, nor had any children, and died at a relatively young age of 48. Fortunately, through his appreciation of a young Helen Keller, we learn much more about Raleigh.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:52078/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:52078/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The history we learn is written through the lens of the rich, famous and powerful. Unfortunately, these people are only partially relateable. They may&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is another, more compeling view of history, seen through the rich tapestry of the lives of everyday common people. The challenge with telling this story is the facts are scarce and hard to uncover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog seeks to discover, document and elucidate the origins of William Iiams, a colonial settler in the Province of Maryland in British America in the mid-17th century.  The first record we have of William is his marriage to Elizabeth Cheyney in 1671 at All Hallow&amp;rsquo;s Parish located along the banks of the South River in Anne Arundel, Maryland approximately 6 miles to the west of Annapolis.  William, like most setters of area, was a tobacco farmer. There is no record of how, or when William arrived in the New World, or where he came from. Family lore from a diverse group of descendants describes the family as being of Welsh origin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
